solocheck.ie 2019-05-09

# Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy - Irish Company Info - SoloCheck

SoloCheck.ie is operated by CRIF VisionNet Limited. With this Privacy Policy, CRIF VisionNet Limited, intends to describe the personal data collected by the company, how it is used including the methods adopted in the management of this website with reference to the processing of its users' personal data. This is a general notice, available to all those who consult the website, in compliance with the provisions of the EU's General Data Protection Regulation 679/2016 (the GDPR), the Irish Data Protection Acts 1988 to 2018, the European Communities (Electronic Communications Networks and Services) (Privacy and Electronic Communications) Regulations 2011 and other applicable laws. When using certain services, users will be provided with specific and detailed privacy notices in accordance with Articles 13 or 14 of the GDPR as appropriate.

### The Data Controller

The data controller is:  
CRIF VisionNet Limited, with a registered office at:  
3rd Floor, Adelphi Plaza, George's Street Upper, Dun Laoghaire, County Dublin, A96 T927  
Company number: 177790  
Correspondence concerning personal data can be addressed to the Data Protection Officer or by emailing [privacy@solocheck.ie](mailto:privacy@solocheck.ie). 

### Categories of Personal Data Collected

#### Personal data not collected directly from data subjects

  * Names, job titles and addresses (postal and electronic) of directors and other office holders in registered companies (e.g. Secretary), date of birth, duration of directorships/offices held
  * Names, job titles and addresses (postal and electronic) of sole traders, partners or other unincorporated entities, date of birth, duration of business arrangement
  * Names, addresses (postal and electronic) of shareholders of companies, duration of shareholding
  * Persons Entitled
  * Names, postal addresses of Liquidators, Receivers and Examiners, date of appointment
  * Authorised Persons, Business Owners
  * Names and Addresses of individuals deemed to be "Politically Exposed Persons" classified by proximity
  * Names, postal addresses of Auditors
  * Date of adjudication of Bankrupts and date of their discharge
  * Names and postal addresses of individuals with consumer/bad debt Judgments
  * Names and postal addresses of individuals entering into Personal Insolvency arrangements
  * Names and postal addresses of individuals entering into Debt Settlement arrangements
  * Names and postal addresses of individuals entering into Debt Relief arrangements
  * Names and postal addresses of those availing of Protective Certificates
  * Names and postal addresses of Disqualified or Restricted Persons
  * Names and postal addresses of individuals entering into Revenue Commissioner agreements
  * Names and postal addresses of individuals deemed to be Beneficial Owners
  * Names and postal addresses of individuals subject to international sanctions

#### Personal data collected directly whether by use of this website or otherwise

  * Names, email addresses, phone numbers of individuals in client organisations

<

### How Personal Data is Collected by Vision-net & SoloCheck

#### Personal data not collected directly from data subjects

Vison-net draws on a variety of publicly available data sources, in particular the Companies' Registration Office, but also Jordans, RTL, ISI Ireland, Revenue Commissioners (for defaulters) and the Irish Courts amongst others.

#### Personal data collected by use of this website

The information systems and software procedures involved in the operation of this site acquire certain personal data during their normal operation. The transmission of this data is implicit in the use of Internet communication protocols. This information is not collected in order to be associated with identified parties, however, due to its very nature, it could make it possible to identify users through processing activity and association with data held by third parties. The type of data acquired includes IP addresses and the domain names of users' computers who connect to the site, the addresses of the resources requested in URI notation (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time the request was made, the method used in making the request to the server, and other parameters related to the operating system and the computer environment of the user.

The optional and voluntary sending of emails to the addresses indicated on the site, or by completing contact forms or other forms on the site, involves the acquisition of the user's personal data, necessary in order to respond to their requests. You are free to decide whether to provide the personal data necessary for CRIF VisionNet Limited to supply the requested services. There are specific Privacy Notices at such points that tell you what we will do with that data as required by Article 13 of the GDPR. Failure to provide this data may make it impossible for CRIF VisionNet Limited to supply the requested information or services.

#### Other ways in which we collect personal data

We can also collect such data from meetings with you, any client on-boarding forms you might complete or communications received from you or an intermediary acting on your behalf.

### Processing Methods

The data shall be processed in a lawful fashion, so as to ensure data security and confidentiality, as foreseen by GDPR provisions and all applicable laws. Personal data shall be processed using electronic or other automated means.

### Purposes of Processing

CRIF VisionNet is an aggregator of business information in order to provide services to those striving to reduce business risk, fulfil compliance requirements and make informed business decisions. These can include searches on directorships, Know Your Customer (KYC), Anti-Money Laundering (AML) and Politically Exposed Persons (PEPs). In doing so, CRIF VisionNet necessarily processes data on individuals associated with companies or otherwise offering products or services.

The data gathered from users of this website shall be processed so that we can provide services to our clients, record visitors to our site, identify users who download reports or other material from the site and build up a contacts database for direct marketing purposes. This data may also be used to contact clients who may have breached our copyright or other terms and conditions.

### Ground of Processing

The data shall be processed on the basis of our legitimate interests in:

  * providing services to our clients, such as company searches, anti-money laundering (AML), know your customer (KYC) or other compliance searches, credit reports and risk ratings, business lists and related services;
  * promoting our business;
  * inviting you to events, seminars, webinars, etc;
  * developing and maintaining business relationships;
  * administrative and operational processes within our business;
  * protecting the security and integrity of our IT systems and online platforms;
  * managing and administering our relationship with business contacts, clients and potential clients;
  * sending you marketing material, newsletters, and other information, unless you opt-out of receiving marketing communications which you will be offered on each occasion;
  * monitoring and analysing your receipt of, and interest in, material we send you;
  * analysing visitors to our website;
  * analysing who is interested in material we publish on our site and what material is of most interest;
  * ensuring clients comply with our Terms & Conditions

When we process your Personal Data based on our legitimate interests, we make sure to consider and balance any potential impact on you and your data protection rights. We will not use your Personal Data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted by law).   
In certain circumstances we may rely on your consent to send you electronic direct marketing communications. 

### Categories of Recipients of the Personal Data

Users of our services will have access to the personal data that forms part of our core services to allow them minimise business risk by informing themselves about parties with whom they might be engaging. While there are individuals working for companies across all sectors, there is a particularly high proportion of financial services companies as well as legal and financial practices.

We may disclose some or all of the Personal Data we collect from you to certain trusted third parties in accordance with contractual arrangements we have in place with these third parties, including:

  * third parties who assist us in marketing and promoting the firm;
  * suppliers and service providers to whom we outsource support services,
  * IT service providers;

We may also share your data if it is a legal or regulatory requirement, e.g., if a law enforcement official asks us for information about you, we may disclose that information where necessary to do so.

### Data Transfer

In some circumstances, CRIF VisionNet Limited transfers personal data outside the European Union, particularly to companies who provide support services. However, when personal data will be transferred outside the European Union, the transfer will be put in place in accordance with provisions of GDPR and all applicable laws (as specified in each privacy notice).

### Retention Periods for Personal Data

We will only keep data which we have received from other publicly available sources on our systems for as long as they are available from the originating sources.

We will keep and process your Personal Data where you have been a client or representative of a company with an active account with us for a period of one year after the last interaction or the closure of your account, after which we will keep aggregated information (which will not allow individuals to be identified) for analytics purposes.

If you wish to opt out of receiving marketing emails, newsletters or other such communications, you may do so at any time by emailing us at [privacy@solocheck.ie](mailto:privacy@solocheck.ie). In addition, all electronic communications you receive from us will include clear instructions as to how you can withdraw your consent to receiving any further communications. However, we may need to retain some identifying information to enable us to ensure that we do indeed suppress any future communications.

### Cookie Policy  

SoloCheck.ie respects the privacy of all visitors to our website. This text outlines our policy around our use of cookies. Our Cookie Policy may be updated from time to time to reflect any changes in technology or legislation which may affect the way in which cookies are used by us and how you as a user, can manage them.

#### What is a Cookie

Cookies are small pieces of data given to your browser by a website, which may be stored as text files in the cookie directory of your computer. Cookies are not programs and cannot collect information from your computer. A cookie can be used for authentication, storing site preferences, shopping cart contents, the identifier for a server-based session...  
To protect your privacy your browser only returns a cookie to the website that sent you the cookie and does not send it to any other website. A website cannot access your cookie directory or information on your computer, instead relevant cookies are included by your browser within each request you make to the website.  
You do not have to accept cookies and you can change the settings within your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, reject cookies from certain websites, notify you if a site is requesting to set a cookie, and set various other options.  
Switching off cookies will still allow you to view the logged out sections on our site, however, it will prevent you from logging in. It will also stop us from remembering your login name. 

#### Cookies used on SoloCheck.ie

Type| Expiration| Description  
---|---|---  
Session/Login Cookies| End of browser session| In order for our server to recognise a logged in user, a session cookie must be used. When a user first enters SoloCheck.ie, they are assigned a cookie which is then used to identify them throughout their session. The information passed does not contain or relate to any personal information.  
Username Cookie| 31 days from last login| Many users prefer not to have to remember their username on a website, therefore by default we store the latest username in a cookie for successful logins.   
Analytics Cookies| Maximum 2 years from set/update| These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site, which we use to help improve it. The cookies collect information in an **anonymous** form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. We use one of the most frequently used suppliers for this.  
Cookie cookie| 60 days from set/update| We provide an option to "Hide this message" about cookies, which itself requires a cookie. This cookie is only written to your computer if you click the "Hide this message" link.  

To learn more about managing cookies view your web browser help or visit [European Cookie Information Website](http://ec.europa.eu/ipg/basics/legal/cookies/index_en.htm)

### Remarketing

External pages on SoloCheck.ie contain Google remarketing tags. These tags are used by third-party vendors, including Google, to re-advertise SoloCheck.ie and its related reports and services across the Internet. Remarketing third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a users' past visits to various pages of our website. Visitors can opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting [Google's Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). Alternatively, you can opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

### Data Subject Rights

We also inform you that you may have the right to request of us access to, and rectification or erasure, of personal data or the restriction of processing concerning your data or to object to processing as well as the right to data portability. Furthermore, to the extent that our processing may be based on consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before this withdrawal. Please bear in mind that your rights in relation to your Personal Data are not absolute.

You may be asked for additional data to verify your identity in the event that you do request access to your personal data held by us. This will only be used for verification purposes, not stored, and securely destroyed once the request has been processed. For such Data Subject Access Requests we will provide the information requested within one month of receipt of a valid request. That period may be extended by two further months where necessary, taking into account the complexity and number of the requests. We will inform you of any such extension within one month of receipt of the request, together with the reasons for the delay.

You can exercise your rights in relation to your Personal Data by contacting:  
Data Protection Officer, CRIF VisionNet Limited, 3rd Floor, Adelphi Plaza, George's Street Upper, Dun Laoghaire, County Dublin, A96 T927

For Subject Access Requests we will provide the information requested within one month of receipt of a valid request. That period may be extended by two further months where necessary, taking into account the complexity and number of the requests. We will inform you of any such extension within one month of receipt of the request, together with the reasons for the delay.

You also have a right to complain to the Data Protection Commission at info@dataprotection.ie, or in writing to:  
Data Protection Commission, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, Co. Laois, R32 AP23, Ireland.  

### Updates and Changes

We may amend this policy on occasion, in whole or part, at our sole discretion. Any changes will be effective immediately. You should check this page from time to time to take notice of any changes we make, as they will be binding on you.

**Last Updated:** 13/07/2018
